Finding Aid for Regina Hay papers, 1930-1966
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Regina Hay papers 1930-1966
Hay, Regina, 1896-
2 linear feet, 2 oversize volumes, and 1 oversize folder
85200 Aa 2; AC; UAm
Republican Party official from Romeo, Michigan, National Republican Committeewoman, secretary of the Republican National Convention, 1948. Correspondence, scrapbooks, political miscellanea and photographs largely relating to the Republican National Convention held in Philadelphia and the election of 1948.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mr. and Mrs. Thomas R. Deem (donor no. 6194 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Regina Hay was a Republican Party official from Romeo, Michigan. She served as Republican National Committeewoman, and in 1948, she was secretary of the Republican National Convention.
The Regina Hay collection documents her work with the state and national Republican Party. The correspondence relates primarily to her work in the election of 1948, especially in the period leading up to the party's national convention. The scrapbooks provide excellent documentation of her entire political career beginning in the 1930s and culminating in the election of Dwight Eisenhower.
Subjects:
Presidents--United States--Election--1948.; Republican National Convention (24th: 1948: Philadelphia, Pa.); Republican Party (Mich.); Republican National Committee (U.S.); Romeo (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1933-1953.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; Women in politics--United States.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Hay, Regina, 1896-; Political elections.; Republican National Convention (24th: 1948: Philadelphia, Pa.); Republican National Committee (U.S.); Republican Party (Mich.); Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Women.; Alger, Frederick Moulton, 1907-1967.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Crooks, Richard, 1900-1972.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Photographs
  - Celebrities, friends (Box 1)
  - Groups (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    (see also oversize folder UAm)
- Correspondence
  - 1941-1945 (Box 1)
  - Undated and January-March 1948 (Box 1)
  - April-May 1948 (Box 1)
  - June 1-10, 1948 (Box 1)
  - June 11-20, 1948 (Box 1)
  - June 21-30, 1948 (Box 1)
  - July 1948 (Box 1)
  - August-September 1948 (Box 1)
  - October-December 1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949-1966 (Box 1)
- Republican Party materials
  - Republican Party National Convention papers, 1948, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Republican Party miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Guest book (Box 1)
  - Book of testimonial letters, 1945 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1940-1948 (loose items), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1950-1952 (loose items) (Box 1)
  - 1953 (loose items) (Box 1)
  - 1930-1936 (Box 2)
  - 1936-1940 (Box 2)
  - 1940-1943 (Box 2)
  - 1944-1947 (Volume 1)
    (outsize volume)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  - 1950-1952 (Volume 2)
  - 1951 largely containing get-well cards to Dudley Hay after automobile accident (Box 2)